all right welcome to
my really messy room
um you know I thought about doing a
doing a video today and I was like do I
really want to have people see how messy
this room
is and the answer is
yes I don't want to hide anything from
you I uh
I'm
real and this is this is my adventure
cycling
mess um I'm currently in the middle of
cleaning up this room obviously and so
this is my yoga room but I'm going to go
ahead and talk about yoga
today um I'm actually G to try to post
this video to YouTube as
well
um just with the hope that we can get
more people to do yoga I am playing
music externally
so if you're coming for the music this
is not going to be the video for you
you're going to probably want to
do something else um since this is the
first yoga video I'm going to put on
YouTube I'm going to go ahead
and talk about myself just a little bit
so um you know long time athlete since I
was a kid and and been doing yoga PR and
in 20 was it 16 I got licensed I got you
know I got
trained um at the stronga yoga
Institute and it's been a while I
actually went through a period of like
real serious
um uh loss of
health and because of coding and
streaming and stuff and some of the
people on my Liv stream know about this
but I want to talk about it um it's been
a long road back to health and so in
fact I started doing yoga about a year
ago and started messing with my wrists
and stuff because I have was too
heavy
so um so this this is a video to just
kind of put it all out there I just
realized I have my Bernie 2016 shirt on
it's kind of appropriate because the
2016 is when
um uh that's when I I'm pretty sure
that's when I went to training and
everything and actually if you dig
really hard you can go to my
um to my uh skill stack uh Twitter feed
and you can see my the first class of uh
people that I graduated from yoga
training with um so I have a lot of
memories of that I'm just going to talk
about this this if you're here for yoga
though I am going to talk
through
um my own personal development this is
more of a vlog than it is an
instructional video
um just like my cycling videos so this
is this is not as much about me telling
you what to do as much as it is um me
talking through what I'm doing and why
I'm doing it and the reason I decided to
do this today today instead of just put
the music on and do my practice is
because um I I'm a little concerned by
streaming
yoga that somebody's going to see it and
they're going to try to do what I do so
I do handstands I do back bends I do uh
depending on the day um I do a lot of
stuff that if a beginner were to try it
they would actually get really hurt and
I actually have hurt myself in the past
by doing more than than I could and
so you know I'm either not going to
stream it and just have my own personal
practice which I'm probably going to
return to some of that more or I am
going to treat it like a yoga class uh
yoga vog and I'm going to talk about
what I'm doing and why you might want to
do it and why you might not want to do
it and why you might want to mod it
because I feel kind of irresponsible as
a as a you know sort of yoga instructor
not talking about those things um
because it's really important if you if
you like tweak your neck or something I
mean there's a lot of ways you can
really seriously hurt yourself doing
yoga and uh
Soh I figured I'd start by saying I know
that's a lot of talking so let's get on
it um the first thing I want to talk
about
is your gear right if you're going to
get into yoga um you just need a mat I
would get a manduka mat because they
last forever and they're really comfy uh
they're super expensive but those other
P mats you'll you'll chip them up and
you'll throw them away every year so get
a manduka and just call it a day and um
and as for clothing you really don't
have to have any fancy clothing if
you're bald like me you might need
something to keep the sweat off your
head um I don't even think I'm going to
sweat that much today um if you you can
do I deliberately wore my jammies in my
t-shirt today there's no uniform for
yoga I had
somebody
yesterday uh two days ago suggest in the
chat that you invest in you know a good
a good set of Lulu man yoga gear and I
don't agree I don't agree I think you
should be able to do yoga in anything
that allows your body to move um and
that's it is it it means your pajamas if
you want um I mean you know these are
just Cheapo banana [__]
pajamas and they feel they feel
fantastic and they're going to get
sweaty and everything and you're going
to be doing lots of laundry one of the
nice things about doing it in pajamas is
you could just wake up and do yoga in
your
pajamas you know it depends on how you
sleep or something all right well I'm
already feeling it um okay so the other
thing you need to know uh as I'm as I'm
going into this is that I am
doing uh today I'm going to be doing
something new and I'm going to be
experimenting with different poses
um that both build core strength but
also don't Tire me out too much because
I've been doing
uh two to three hours of um you know
sometimes low intensity sometimes high
intensity cycling every day so uh and
you know there's videos on that on
YouTube and you can go watch that and
come with me join me and I really really
enjoy my cycling um I actually consider
it kind of a practice you know a yoga
practice a cycling practice I do it
every day um it you know it just totally
changes my soul and puts a nice you know
period punctuation on the work day and
so I can you know move into relaxing
with my wife at night I mean there's
just a million reasons I love cycling
and yoga and cycling actually go
together really well but there there are
a couple of considerations so one of
them is that depending on the type of
cycling you're doing and whether you're
competitive or not the cycling is really
going to take it out of you it's really
going to take a lot out of your body and
if you do a stronger
practice um there's not going to be as
as much opportunity for you to
um to get the most out of aanga uh you
know if you're looking for strength core
strength gains and if you're if you're
looking at yoga as a low intensity um
aerobic exercise which it is if you do
if you do aanga or or batist or you know
any of these other Yoga practices where
you're you tend to sweat a lot um Yin
Yoga is focused on
flexibility and I mean there's just tons
and tons of of areas of yoga and so one
of the reasons I want to actually do a
little bit of blah blah blah during
these yoga sessions is as I'm doing
particularly Yin Yoga I'm going to be
able to talk a lot during it now the
first thing that I have a problem with
there is that talking is actually
distracting from the goal of original
yoga the
yoga it
means stopping the spinning or the
fluctuation of your brain that's the
purpose of yoga above everything else
all this fancy sitting and headstands
and everything that is not yoga those
those are part of Asa which is one of
eight limbs of yoga and actually debated
about whether we should just have a
talkie-talkie session on on um on
Fridays I mean on Saturday when is
normally the day off or shanga and I've
decided that in order to keep this fun
for me um to give up some of those
opportunities for meditative practice uh
and and you know unless I'm going to do
and I'll we'll talk about it and we'll
actually do a little bit of meditation
and I'll just prompt and I'll talk
through it so um if you want to follow
along with me on that you should be able
to do that um and I'm going to start
approaching this as a absolute beginner
yoga class um and I feel like that'll be
enough to get me loosened up for the day
and uh to get keep my core strength and
still allow me to do some um Stu it also
means you're not going to there not
going to be a lot of heavy
breathing I mean there will be heavy
breathing I promise but but but uh
that's not the highlight of course um in
terms of answering chat I'm as as with
anything I'm going to take an
opportunity to check the chat every once
in a while but other than that I'm going
to leave chat off um so
uh uh GNA go great thank you IPO
um I I like your yoga tone is peaceful
thank you so um again we're not going to
be reading a lot of chat I will take
breaks to read the chat on occasion
answer questions um and I'll do a Q&A at
the end as well so if You' had a
question about that is practice but the
other reason for that is because I do
want to at least maintain some sort of
like meditative State as we go through
it even though I'm going to be prompting
for a lot of this okay and I'm going to
be doing different styles of yoga we're
not necessarily going to do yoga in the
the order that everybody always does and
the yoga that I do is going to be
adapted for beginners and for old people
like me you know um so anyway let's go
um I'm going to turn the music up and
then we'll leave the chat here we come
back to that
later and I don't know if I'm going to
get demonetized or muted because of the
music I guess we'll find out
this is this song is a really good
um I wish I could skip on this this does
not skip I wish it
did you know what I can do that on my
spottify here let's try that I want to
get the right music for
the I you I don't use Music In Yoga a
lot of times I'll just not not do it at
all but uh and just let the breath be
the thing that you have a pattern to
all right
um the music is too high let me know I
can turn it
down all right so we're gonna actually
start all of the practices with building
a little bit of heat in the
body and some of the stuff I'm going to
say is going to sound really it's going
to sound like yoga guy and I don't like
that you know like oh we're going to
build heat in the body right
I I don't like sounding like you know a
yoga dude but that's what we're doing
I'm gonna say it so we're going to be
building a little bit of heat in the
body why are we building heat in the
body because nobody every you probably
know this cold muscles are bad they're
they're bad to stretch you don't want to
ever stretch cold and especially with
Yin Yoga we have to build up some heat
in the in the body so you probably
shouldn't do yoga for sing you should
probably wait if you haven't
um if you haven't uh avoided that's
another yoga way to say took a [__] um
then you might want to you might want to
do that you might want to wake up a
little bit early maybe have a date and
some peons and some coffee or tea and
let your your body
process um there's a saying in asanga
yoga coffee is Prana uh charlot I think
uh said that he's a um a Big Yoga guy
who runs the shanga yoga Institute now
they that his his dad Tabby Joyce died
Tabby Joyce being the father of
aanga um
and
so you know you should be you should be
largely kind of empty down here right
don't have any food in your
system right after you do yo it's a good
time to go get a smoothie and we'll talk
about that later all right so we're
going to build some heat so we're going
to do um uh we're going to do a lot of
what's called a sun a sun salutation
um we will not do the invocation today
the asanga invocation bndy you know
we're not going to do that todaya has
chanting this is this is just you know
we're just going to build heat in the
body so how do you do a sun a uh so Sun
salutation um you know you just lift
your arm straight up so the arms up
right you try to keep your flat back you
can look
up and then you okay fold over and keep
your back flat and then let it curve out
let it let your back curve this this is
where the mic's going to be kind of
screwed up actually I'm going to try
something I'm going to put the mic on my
my glasses since it's kind of held in
place you guys tell me if that works out
okay it looks weird but it's better than
because then when I bend like this it's
not going to sound weird okay now just
let your arms hang for a second okay now
I'm just showing you how to do this for
now but normally you'll do this in kind
of a flow State and you'll combine it
with your your breathing and we'll do
some of those but I want you to so you
don't have to touch the ground people
you can hold your arms if you want some
people do that you can shake your head
out if you want loosen your neck the
whole point of these sun salutations is
to build heat and some you know
beginning flexibility before you do the
rest okay and then we're just going to
bend over again kind of weaken your body
up and then you can eventually you can
do a little hop here but for right now
let's just step back straight arms under
your
shoulders okay and then you go down but
don't go down farther see my upper arm
is parallel with my body okay don't go
down farther than that
okay and then you're going to curve up
and look up now you see I my toes are
still on the mat but if you want you can
roll your toes forward when you do
that and just arch your back if you want
you can put your knees
down if it's still hard for you to
control it you can stay here for a bit
kind it feels so good guy like me who
hunches over all the time on his butt
bike this feels so good okay now we're
going to push back
up and as much as we can we're going to
try to keep our arms
flat you want to make an l and you want
to make that L hit the ground so that
your hand is solid on the
ground then try to keep your back
flat if you don't do it perfectly it's
okay and
then we're going we're going to gently
never ever ever never bounce never ever
ever bounce can I say that again never
bounce I saw somebody on Twitch bouncing
in their stretches the other day just
been crunching so hard this is one of
the reasons I'm doing
this this a Sure Fire way to rip a
muscle um and if you if you have to have
your knees bent that's fine you can
actually if you're you might even hear
your back crack a little bit when you do
this okay so that's five in andout
breaths okay let me go forward and hold
yourself up and kind of have a plank
pose I'm doing it slow so you can see
the
form all right then you bring one foot
up another foot
up bend
over that's what she
said and then we're going to go
up you can touch your hands to close
your hands together if you can my
shoulders don't really work that well so
I just keep my head
straight and then
down some he and you can you should just
feel fantastic just after doing one
sunsation like that I do I feel like my
whole body is already started to release
right it's already started to release
tension and even though it's really
driving me crazy how messy this room is
all right so let's do another one this
time I'm going to do it with the
breathing okay I'm going to call out the
breathing not how to do the pose so
inhale arms
up exhale
hold inhale flop
back exhale
plank inhale up dog
exhale downward facing dog that's what
those are
called five
breaths if you can't support that it's
okay to put your knees down do it like
this
this isn't a competition people don't do
this like you would do
P90X even though that's where I first
started doing
yoga Tony Horton Tony Horton the guy
that started the entire CrossFit
movement he calls yoga The Fountain Of
You the elixir of
Life inhale exhale
down inhale all the way up dude's in his
upper 60s might even be 70 now he still
does yoga videos on
P90x in fact he doesn't do the p9x stuff
anymore the CrossFit he focuses on
yoga yeah go look it up yeah the entire
CrossFit movement cross X P90X Tony
Horton started the entire cross movement
guess what he's doing now
yoga
exhale inhale
exhale inhale up
dog
exhale one
breath two
three
four
five now you can actually go up on your
toes stretch those toes when you're
going up feels so good in your toes
doesn't it
and then all the way
up one more
hold on
what okay and we're going to do
something called a
sunb if you just learn Sun a you're
doing yoga if you do sun A's Flex pretty
much every part of the body for the most
part wake you all up the sun B is a
little
harder um and it kind of intensifies the
heat you probably already have pill
yourself sweating right now and that
might be an uper yin yoga but I did want
to show you Sun be we'll do a couple of
these a sun be is the same as a sun a
except for it has a word in the middle
so let's do it oh and it starts out with
bent knees instead so you bend your
knees sunbe arms
up same thing fold
over flat
back you can put your feet back or you
can hop back
plank up dog again like sun
a Down dog like sun
be and this time we rotate our left
foot a little bit we lift this foot up
and we Throw It Forward kind of by this
front hand see where I'm
at and then on our inhale we go
up and then we have an
exhale and put the foot
back go
down come up or up
dog downward facing dog then right into
the next
leg rotate the foot other foot
forward and you might have to lick your
your lift your foot forward when you're
first starting
out and then go
up on the
inhale and then
down put the foot back I don't know if
you saw that but I almost put my foot
right where my hand is can you see that
you probably can't see it here let
me so I usually put my foot almost right
where my hand is and then when I come
down I put my hands like kind of right
where my foot's going to go and I move
my foot out of the way and put it back
and
down up
dog then all the way back to downward
facing dog for five
breaths if you want you can bend one
knee and kind of rock back a little
bit but don't bounce
remember all right
now again
inhale
exhale we go all the way up but this
time we Bend our
legs no I'm I'm breathing really fast
right now I don't know about you and
that's what you want in fact when you
first start
out when you first start
out I let's talk about Suns for a bit my
heart rate comes down fact I should
probably put my heart rate on the screen
Sun
situtations are for lots of reasons one
of them is that we talked about is
building heat in the body I'm plenty hot
heart is going the way you know that
you're plenty hot is when your breathing
is faster than you can do the poses so
like I was right at the end of that last
one I was trying to go up right I was
trying to go up and I was
like right and that was when I knew that
okay I've got enough heat in my body so
if you're doing this Sun if you're doing
the sun salutations to build heat in
your body so that your muscles are
warmed up and you can do the rest like Y
Yoga I'm good right now right now I'm
done but there's a second reason to do
sun salutations my wife Doris who's also
you know a certified yoga instructor has
taught in several several different
places she regularly uses Sunsations as
a
workout she would she would in her hide
of her hide of her day when I met her
she was doing 30 to 50 sunsight
rotations every day
and she used that as her workout so and
she would not have the pauses in between
she would not end at the end of it she
would go she would do her yoga and she
would just go and she would keep jumping
she would just keep doing sun
salutations so um on summer solstice
they also do 108 which is kind of a
magic number in the yoga World um
Sunsations and they would just keep
doing them and I promise you and you can
do you can either do sun a or sun b i I
don't know if you saw it but sun b is
like you know they hit your legs a lot
more right
um now I'm a cyclist and I need my legs
later for today so I can bike so I'm not
going to by the way if you do um you
don't if you don't want to burn your
quads out during yoga you can
modify by you can make the intensity on
your leg um harder or easier based on
how low you go right if you go all the
way down you're going to get a good you
know
um uh stretch in your Sor what is it I
want to say psorasis SK Solosis or
whatever the thing is I have to look at
the name of it even though I had to P
anatomy and I don't
remember what's the thing what's the
thing that connects from right here to
here it goes down here look it's a it's
it's a hard thing I keep get about
anyway you can you can validate you can
change your intensity by going up or
down right okay so bottom line um I'm
hot I'm swe my pajamas and my clothes
are covered in sweat already because I
kind of worked out from before so you
can do it I just wanted to say you can
either do yoga to you can do sun
salutations to build heat uh you can do
sun salutations as a low low uh aerobic
workout that includes you know strength
training and you can do sun salutations
to
um uh as for meditative sort of thing so
if you do like sun sun A's are not as
intense and they're actually really
great way if your brain is going nuts
and you don't want to think about it
it's kind of a cheap form of taichi
right you can just do sunas and listen
to your breath and I promise you after
five or 10 of those whatever problems
were in your head or something like that
they'll seem much more manageable
because you'll you'll kind of like
silence the the the fluctuations of the
mind that's what yoga
is so all right so we've we've done our
sons now normal right now in a stronger
practice I would start to do all the
hamstring stretches of standing we're
not going to do that okay um the reason
I'm not going to do that there's like
balance poses and all kinds of stuff for
a strong eye will'll do that another day
today the only goal is for me to relieve
the tension and to recover from the
cycling I did yesterday so I'm
personally going to to experiment with
some poses and I'm going to show you how
to build your own practice uh which is
the ultimate goal is to build your own
practice not to go to you know pay bucks
and go to some yoga studio I mean you
can do that if you want the community
and everything but that that is not what
yoga is about yoga is about building a
personal practice it's that helps you
it's about something you do in your at
your house on your own time for free
it's not it's not something that you
know it's been sensationalized and
commercialized that's not the purpose of
yoga never has been by the way well I
don't know Krishna machar had did kind
of sell his soul so that to the maharaji
to do performance all the all the
performance yoga ever heard about it was
him trying to impress the maharaji you
know the ultra rich maharaji and all of
his cronies so that he'd get more money
so yoga was asaga yoga was actually
invented to tame uh you know tweenage
boys and to chill them out uh but it
goes back much farther than that and
we'll talk about that later but there's
going to be a lot of talking today
because this is the first video and
several I know with my Messi yoga this
room sort of represents my beginner yoga
mind right I've got all sorts of things
going on I'm not practicing saucha which
is cleanliness which we'll talk about so
where my body's warm and my heart I can
talk now so now I know I can go
down um let's ask let's let's answer any
questions that have come in actually let
me fix the video there the camera we're
going to be doing mostly seated yoga
today
and
um so see if there's any questions
before we move on really
quick it's a modified version of s and
the
mascara um the first time I did up dog
POS this I Heaven it was really nice see
that's
great
namaskar namaskar A and namas B those
are the two that we
did yeah all right
so let's
uh we talking about up dog poses and
he's using the Sanskrit names which I
memorize Once Upon a Time all right so
that's just me naturally don't try to do
that you're not ready for that yet okay
so if if you're beginning
um there there are act okay let's do
this you see how I just plop down on the
mat there's actually a more elegant
meditative way to get yourself into
sitting position and you can probably
guess it involves a sun salutation in
fact the the reason it's so important
you learn those sun salutations is in
asanga yoga or even in power yoga or
batist yoga it they are the things that
the the Vasa they are the flow they are
the things that link the poses together
so that's the goal whatever you end up
doing make sure you try to link stuff
together so let's do a sun
a call
it say that five times fast
okay so from here you can kind of push
your your hands up right and then you
can bring one leg to your chest bring
the other leg to the chest and the goal
eventually is to bring your legs through
to the front now if you can't do that
right now obviously that's not a big
deal I still
can't you can sit down when you get good
though you can do that and go all the
way to the front when you get really
flexible you can actually keep your legs
straight and go right through but that's
not for everybody and that's actually
one of the things that I was very happy
to learn in yoga training I was feeling
so bad because I couldn't do you know a
proper jump through you can go look at
the US and you know crazy people that
are really great and they have standing
you know what my arms are too
short I will never be able to do a
standing jump through ever the only way
I could ever do it would be to have a a
block we'll talk about assist in a
second that's it
so don't let anybody to tell you you're
doing it wrong when you you got to
listen to your body it's a very personal
thing so you know there are some things
that are you should probably listen to
somebody
about so the first thing you probably
want to do when you get into a sitting
pose I'm going to talk about some stuff
that's really weird so your ass cheeks
we're going to talk about your ass
cheeks for a second all right what you
want is you want to be grounded right
you want to be grounded it might be hard
for you to even sit like this right now
that's fine you know keep your hands
back here but we're going to talk about
your ass cheeks I know this is really
gross but I promise you try this and you
w love it spread your ass cheeks so
you'll see people in Y Yoga they'll
reach around and grab their ass and then
grab their other ass cheek try it try it
right oh doesn't that feel good so you
just got you just got all of your glute
muscles out of the way and now your sit
bones underneath there those sit bones
are making direct contact with the
ground this is very grounded and if you
have a nice mat under you it just feels
glorious um it's just you just feel
really based just really grounded hey
Bast is both a common
cool that's so cool Bast is like what
the young kids would say and it's also
relevant shocking okay
so we're just gonna sit here for a bit
now you can sit here like this try to
keep her head straight keep your back
straight as hard as you can I'm probably
going to fail I regularly think that my
back is straight and then I look at the
video and I'm like you know it's not
straight and by the way nothing wrong
with videoing yourself and then watching
your own videos it's the best way for
you to give yourself your own if you
don't the best way obviously is to go to
a studio like a stronga studio or
something where you have somebody who's
personally mentoring you you have a
private instructor that's by far the
best way but not everybody can do that
or afford that so just taking a PCT just
taking video of your swimmers do this
all the time too by the way swimmers
will put a camera and they'll watch
themselves in the lane and then they'll
go watch their video to check on their
stroke just stretching your my
neck now normally I wouldn't be talking
so much I'd be like listening to my body
where like you know what is going on in
my body what is what needs work right
now right and this is we're going to use
kind of an Adaptive practice today which
is fine it's totally fine some people
will tell you oh no benefit it you know
because you didn't do the right order
[__] that [__] that you're going to do
yoga for you and you need to listen to
your body and find out what's going on
with your body and right now my body
says you know my hamstrings are a little
tight my shoulders are a little tight my
neck is still a little tight because you
know
biking and so I'm just doing some arm
head rotations not too much don't push
it because you end up pulling something
and I'm just doing a little bit to
loosen up my neck
this one oh my God that one feels so
good I'm just tilting my my head to the
right and now I'm tilting my head to the
left and I'm still just sitting here the
reason for that because the hamstrings
are kind of loosening up and the tension
is leaving a lot of the reasons people
can't stretch is because they're just so
tense and I'm just letting myself get
untense for a
bit all right okay so now that I'm sort
of untense time to do a different pose
now we haven't done any serious forward
bending yet so we don't have to counter
it with uh a POS it's called the counter
pose which kind of bends you the other
way you ever see like a any kind of
plastic you bend it too much eventually
it breaks right uh or if you keep
bending it the same direction it doesn't
Bend back your body's the same so I'm
going to take like a little Indian towel
you can take any kind of towel there's
this kind there's these microle there's
all kind kinds of towels you can use a
strap if you want but I for a towel just
because it's softer I don't like the
feeling of the straps that they use in
yoga they're really uncomfortable so
this is actually really comfortable plus
if I'm sweating it cleans it up and I
can stick it in the wash which you can't
do with a strap oh my God those straps
get so nasty they get so nasty all right
so on the inhale I'm going to straighten
my
back okay on the exhale I'm G to throw
my tow out there I'm keeping my back
straight so this is important
people people think when they do a
forward stretch and there is a reason to
to arch your back but not not right now
so I'm keeping my legs are totally
straight my ass my B my my my um bones
are connected to the ground because I
move my ass glutes out of the way and
and and I am inhaling I'm straightening
my back and I am making my Naval touch
my thigh if you want to you can think of
taking your heart and having your heart
to touch your knees that's the way to
think about this it's not the way it's
not thinking about touching your toes
think about bending yourself so that
your heart is going to touch your knees
and when you do that you notice your
back stays straight and you won't be
able to go as far you
won't you know you won't why because
you're engaging the hamstrings the way
that you know they're supposed to be
engaged and you know I see people do
this incorrectly all the time and I
sometimes do just cuz I want to touch my
toes because that's the stronger way
right no don't you just just keep your
back straight keep your neck
straight and just go as far as you can
and this is no competition don't go too
far just go to the point where your body
stops I'm I'm telling you right now if
you go farther than that you'll end up
pulling something and you won't be able
to bike ride so don't do
that but if you stay here long longer
this Yin Yoga is like 20 seconds it
takes at least 20 seconds in any pose to
get the
effect um it's actually one of the
things I don't like about Ashtanga we'll
talk about asanga more later but asanga
is more like Tai Chi than it is Yoga
because it's it's
designed
to get you into the same flowy
meditative State and they don't care
about the form shat himself if you watch
some of his asanga flows after he turned
50s something and got all inflexible
they AB his form and are absolutely
horrible and that's fine that's aanga
shanga is like let's not hurt ourselves
but let's not focus on that let's focus
on the breath and the meditative State
just like
taii but um but they you'll see the form
go asanga doesn't care about form if you
do batist yoga or iar yoga iar is
obsessed with form the form is the
purpose of yoga yoga is is more of a
prescription for a particular malady um
and iar himself suffered from
tuberculosis and a bunch of really bad
problems he was also completely abused
by the same instructor that Pabi Joyce
had who who tore his hamstrings because
he couldn't do the splits and Chris Mach
came up and slammed him down and ripped
the [__] out of his hamstring and he
quit irar quit and said no I don't need
that [__] went to Puna and created iar
yoga so that's where iar yoga and uh
asanga asanga yoga is basically jock
yoga that's what it is batabi joy is
just a big jock even gets fat in his old
age and blames it on his son dying which
I hate oh my son died I can never do
yoga again [__]
[__] Iron Guard did yoga up until
the day he died no matter how big he got
no matter how fat he was he did yoga his
whole entire life because he did yoga
for different reasons his yoga was for
to be to be restorative so there there's
another thing you don't have to just do
one practice you can pick from lots of
different practices and make it yourself
matd ezrati is my absolute favorite uh
yoga person who has ever lived Maddie
Maddie ezrati you can go look her up and
she's like this New Yorker and she's
like me who cares
right you can do this and you can do
that you know she's like stop being all
messed up about it
right and uh I just love her opinion
she's an absolute she's actually in the
P Joy the stronga yoga video on YouTube
She's the the girl on the far right
closest to the camera
and she's the one who put together uh to
put together the asanga the asanga
sequence on YouTube um before that was
YouTube frankly so anyway so we're just
we're just all we're doing is stretching
both of our legs at the same time and
we're kind of forgetting about it and
I'm talking and talking and talking
obviously in Yin Yoga I can talk I might
feel this sweat on my body has kind of
has kind of evaporated so uh it's
probably time to do a flow and there's
two reasons to do a chaturanga in the
middle or a Vasa whatever you want to
call it chaturanga is kind of part of
the vyasa vyasa is the flow we're going
to go from here and then we're going to
have uh we're going to do basically a
sun salutation to separate this from the
next pose and another thing that does is
it resets your body so right now my
lower back has got a little bit of
tension because it's been kind of
holding me up but my hamstrings feel
nice and loose so it's time for us to do
a
transition all right now
now we're we're just going to get back
to downward dog we're going to get back
to Plank and then we're going to get
back to downward dog right uh and then
we're going to do an up dog and then
we're going to come we're going to jump
through again all right now I think
doing a vyasa even if you're doing Yen
Yoga is a good idea because it does kind
of reset your body mentally it also
mentally you can reset a thing and then
it also kind of builds up more heat so
I'm all cooled off now because I've been
talking and sitting here so let's let's
do a little bit of of the thing now
if this is an opportunity where you can
have fun with this I was a skateboarder
as a kid so I actually do like some of
the tricks you can do in yoga they're
just fun so uh Ken McGregor by the way
talks about she's the big big big big
aranga girl in Florida uh she talks
about coming to yoga because she wanted
to learn how to do kickass handstands
and she says it doesn't matter what
brings you to the mat what matters is
what keeps you on the mat and that you
stay on the mat so if you come to the
yoga because you want to do Kick-Ass
handstands like Kino nothing wrong with
that just you know learn learn to build
up your establish your practice so when
I talk about doing this trick so the
really greatest stronges they'll do this
they'll put their hands right here and
they will lift up all the way and
they'll hold their arms and they'll jump
all the way back but I'm not going to do
that because I
can't so I'm gonna fold my
legs much as I can kind of cheaply like
this right now see if I was good I mean
if I shouldn't say that that's not a
yoga thing to say the way to really do
this is to like bring your knees up to
your chest like this okay and if you
want to get good with this the way to
practice for this is to just hold
yourself like this right and then and
then you push up and flip back so I
can't do it I can't do it I'm out of
practice so what I do instead is I hold
it for a second to build those lower abs
and then I I lean forward and I come up
and I kind of cheat sometimes rather
than put my hands behind my my my feet
right here where they should be
sometimes I cheat right and David
spanson who I consider my Guru who's a
Texan he he talks about all the
different ways you can cheat that are
okay if it's but one of the ways to
cheat and still have a little bit of fun
is to put your hands in front and then
Lean Forward which God the aanga Nazis
would come after me for saying that
right but but if you lean forward a
little bit like this then you can ship
your upper body weight over your hand
hands now the secret to doing a jump
back is weight distribution and when you
once you put your hands
here it's hard to get your legs through
right I mean it's all hard to think
about but once you get your legs here
now you got your up right but as you
lean forward you can feel your legs want
to go back you see how my legs want to
go back so then when you lean forward
I've hit my face on the thing because I
my weight distribution's been Bob before
so so then you then you just forward and
you pop your legs out and then you can
do your up dog toes curled or not up to
you if you want you can put your knees
down and just hold it here I'm going to
hold it here because I really need this
I need this because I hunch over my
whole entire
day so I'm just going to hold that a
little bit more I think we'll probably
do some sink pose later which is
designed to stretch your back out so now
we go back up into up
dog all right
feels so good doesn't it oh that
inversion has something I don't know
what it is it's so magical about it I
think it's the blood going to your
head the blood goes to your head you're
like oh my God that feels so
good I just want to stay here
forever if you need to take a break by
the way you can do downward facing I
mean you can do uh child's POS let me
show you that so this is child's pose
anytime you need to just
restore you can just put your knees
out you can modify child's pose with
your legs out so you can get even
lower child's pose is really really
important because it's a chance for you
to
regroup right you just
regroup so sometimes if you're in that
up dog I'll do a child's pose just to
regroup a but downward facing dog sry I
said I said up dog downward facing dog
is
always a great
thing I always have to spread my fingers
and remind myself to put the weight on
the thumb and four finger right
here all right now we can practice going
through now for this depending on your
mat size I'll bring my hands back
sometimes I'll put my hands off the side
of the mat cuz I'm kind of
wide and I
plank then bring one leg up bring the
other leg up and then go
through then down fun
huh now I'm I am my lower abs are not as
strong as they used to be um I could
regularly do that uh before without
touching I'm G to try one more
time but the way to practice for that is
to bring your leg up and bring your
other leg you
know I can almost do it my toe hits on
the
map little secret here sometimes when
the mat gets sweaty you can just slide
your but just slides goes right
through
okay
so so we
did the up dog and the down dog but the
up dog is what did the counter Poe from
me so I feel like that's good
um let's continue to do the hamstring
stretches
um and we're going to steal from what I
know from the stranga so they call them
the seated poses also if you're going to
be doing a lot of POS Yin poses you can
take this is not something in aanga
pulling out your ass cheeks so your your
your bones to the ground you don't have
time to do that during a stranga but but
during Y Yoga
yeah oh okay now it's just so much
easier to actually just doing that you
may find yourself able to touch your
toes because it just it it it rotates
your hips and it makes it easier for you
to move forward now my back is bent you
see it is still bent a little
bit there are this is something in in
yoga that I first really didn't like I
was kind of That's Not Right But there
are a lot of yoga poses where they
deliberately arch their back
the idea is that they're stretching
their back um and there's some poses
that are like that um if you want to
touch your toes because you already did
it the proper way and stretch your
hamstring and you want to like put your
head down keep your eyes focused on your
toes or your knees is up to you normally
they say toes you can do
that if you want but I don't find that
as I don't find that
as great a sensation as just
just touching my heart to my
knees again okay
so that's both legs let's let's try it
with each leg separate okay so I'm going
to
do this leg so we're going to
do I don't know if I want to show you
all of these the
three uh poses in this set and I forget
the name I I used to remember I used to
um but
I should probably I let me see if I can
read you the name from
from I gu it's been a long time since I
practiced
um bth ASA was the one where we we went
over all the way oh pashima tanasa a b
and
c
um pashima tanasa which is I Used to
Know The Roots I think it's head to foot
I could be wrong you know I'll I'll look
at this if I'm going to keep doing these
videos I need to do I need to study all
my terms again I forgotten them all
because I really don't
care honestly I don't care I just want
the effect so this is you mean like a
runner stretch right everybody's done
this straight leg this foot into
here squared off shoulders there's two
ways to do this you can do it like
this and you know do this thing in fact
they even have a variation of this where
you come up and you fold all the way
around it's got a totally different
effect
for me I just want the hamstring
so I'm going to do the thing again I
could reach down and touch my toes and
Arch my head and touch my forehead to my
knee and the reason I don't like that is
because I it there's too many Sensations
I'm I'm just thinking about the
sensation in my hamstring because that's
the thing I want to have an effect so
heart and staring at my
toe which always makes me want to cut my
toenails which my toenails are perfectly
cut and manicured today
and I'm just bending as far as I can go
straight back with my heart to my
knee my thigh whatever you want to call
it not too far I could get down a lot
farther than this I don't want to go
down farther than this because it'll
overly stretch it and I might end up
doing something that stops me from
riding my
bike or
walking in fact one of the things you
can do instead of instead of even
bending over is you you can arch your
back if you if you arch your back to
make it a little bit straighter a lot of
times it'll end up being actually
straight by doing that because you think
your back was straight but it really
wasn't and then you Archer back and you
can feel the stretch in your hamstring
can't you right if you Archer back you
can feel the stretch in your
hamstring
right and then at the end of this if we
want to spend a little bit of time kind
of you know having fun I do like getting
down close to my knee and hugging my own
leg I know weird right I love the poses
where it feels like you're giving
yourself a big hug and you're like
there's a there's a POS in Pigeon I'll
show you that it's like you're saying
hello foot and your foot's like right in
your face and it's like I haven't seen
you in a while this is really nice let's
have this moment
together I'm not even kidding I really
love it so so to keep your back straight
let's do this and I want you to see my
back will definitely Arch on this I'm
going to Arch back forward as far as you
can if it's up here that's
fine and then we go down and we look the
dreasy should be on the toes but I love
looking at my knee it's like hello
knee this is the closest I've been to my
knee in the last
week I can see my
knee that's one of the things I do like
about yoga is you get
to kind of learn about your your body
all the time I'm my body really wants to
twist today so we're going to do some
merasa but twists are so good for your
back let's just do a few of those don't
overly do it but boy you'll probably
hear your back crack I just
did my back just totally cracked this is
not a this is not a sequency thing this
is just because I want to do
it all right keep the back
straight oh God that feels so good
good oh feels so
wonderful do another
one so
good all right let's just relax and soak
that in for a
second again this is Yin Yoga so it's
about relaxation and flexibility it's
not about you
know sweating really hard like a shonga
feels so good all right so let's do a
Vasa we're going to do a Vasa and we're
going to do the other
leg
and I really should do some mulanda but
I'm not going to because I think we're
running out of time what time is it let
me let me read I tell you what let's do
the other leg and then I'll read chat
all right so again we're going to
practice okay cross your legs put your
hand out see if you can hold that for a
few seconds really bring those knees in
really really bring those knees in
that'll build the muscles you need to do
the jump back the muscles that you need
to be able to do all the really cool
tricks the yoga skater tricks they're
deep deep down inside your abs they're
the lowest of your abs the very low ABS
those are the ABS that make all the
tricks possible because they lock your
legs close to your body and you can feel
it right now if you can't you're
dead right
okay then I'm going to roll forward and
I'm going to jump
back all right you can hold that there
as long as you can take it if you
want Arch that back the other way oh my
God we're g to stay here for a
bit oh God that feels so good oh my God
that feels so good and it's not just
because it looks like I'm [__] my mat
it feels good in my back
I'm
sorry I'm not a very good Yogi I said
[__] you remember those muscles for
doing skate
tricks they also make you really good in
bed I'm not even
kidding
okay what one knee two
knee rotate down all right let's do this
side oh did you hear that pop I hope you
heard that
pop I just got a hip pop those are
great all right now this leg this leg on
my side is really tight I got to be
really careful I do not want to pull it
it is really really
tight
so going to rotate to point
this usually people have that I'm I have
one leg my legs is like uh a centimeter
smaller than the other one and so on the
bike I end up getting
different uh tensions issues with one
leg versus the other one because they're
totally
different usually this knee will hit the
frame top tube of my bike because this
leg is a little longer than the other
one I know it's weird H they have
Orthotics and stuff for that but I don't
do it
oh God feels so
good it's just yoga can be just
stretching like people say or it can be
a badass P90X workout it just depends on
how you approach it that's what's so
great about it this so flexible by the
way this isn't yoga do I need to say
that again this is
AA it's just 1/8 of yoga
ASA sit on your
ASA build an
ASA it means you know sitting or poses
and the the ASA poses are just designed
to prepare your body to meditate that is
the only purpose for the ASA and yet
we've turned yoga and West in particular
we've turned yoga
into P90X
and in that sense it would also turn it
into Physical
Therapy you can pay like 200 bucks an
hour for a physical therapist to tell
you to do cat Cow to relieve the tension
in your shoulders because you need a
breast reduction which my ex-wife
did not I'm not kidding they said what
do they have me do and I she went to
this PT thing and then she came back and
she's like they have me do I have to do
my exercises every day I said you mean
yoga and she's like that's kakow and
like yeah and like how much pay for the
physical therapist to tell you to do cat
cow that's where iar comes in right iar
is Yoga that's designed for physical
therapy I can't go anywhere near that
low on this leg because of my current
situation my hamstring I got to just
relax also bending I don't like bending
my back like that I don't because I do
that with on my bike the bend over thing
I don't need to bend over
that sounded
weird I'm going to Arch my back I want
to Arch it some more we should do a lot
of like back openers because you know
you're always hunched over on the bike
you're always hunched over writing code
I feel like we should do some twists and
some back
openers all right now let's do that jump
back thing
again okay can you hold it up again
we're we're strengthening those low ABS
to while we're practicing our jump
through all right here we go you can if
you want you can lift yourself
up practice holding yourself there
that's
[Music]
hard all right I'm dropping my knees
because I'm going to stay here this is
the back oh God they feels so
good I can feel myself like descending
into
it we're definitely doing
sose definitely doing
SOS
slow oh God I feel so
good all right
now we're going to do some twists
M
and you can do these with your leg out I
like to do them like this if you do it
in stronger you do it like this and then
you do it like this also but this is
more fun the goal of this pose is
rotation of your back in a safe way
you're supposed to move your back you're
supposed to rotate left side right side
forward and back every day I was told
that by a professional in my training
who deals with people the elderly in
retirement homes and she said if you do
that every day that will hydrate the
disc between your spine and your spine
will stay useful into old age as opposed
to drying out and cracking when you bend
over so one thing you should never
especially if you're older one thing you
should never compromise on is you should
make
sure not extremely but to move your back
to its extreme positions every day don't
push it but to do it every day because
that act will actually keep your spine
healthy and God knows I need it my
especially my neck area right here has
got some problems so so what am I doing
I'm holding this one under I'm holding
this one up and actually just keeping
your back straight for a bit like this
and just staying in that pose for a bit
it already is helpful right but we're
going to rotate in two different
directions
here um we're going to put our arm
forward this is one of those aanga
tricks there's actually easier versions
of this pose but this one's kind of fun
so for this I am going to be bending
forward a little bit with my back so
straight arm right and then we're going
to turn our arm going to wrap your arm
you have to bend around this wrap your
arm around your leg now if you can't
touch your body like me or anything so
when you do that it's your your knee is
kind of in your armpit okay and then um
I'm G to take my my towel and I'm going
to throw my towel around and I'm going
to grab it these microle work better for
this kind of thing because they're more
grippy so I have a microle towel I'm
going to throw it around and grab it
with that hand okay then I
inhale inhale straight up you look up
flatten that back straighten it so right
now you can see my spine is kind of
rotates not straight now the goal of
course here is to get it so that your
when you can straighten your back and
you can use that leverage of your arm to
straighten your back keep try to keep
your back straight and try to straighten
out those shoulders now this you're
going to feel a stretch in your upper or
your lower
hamstring and you're also going to kind
of feel it in your back and then as you
exhale we're going to allow our back to
Arch forward and we're going to look
down at our toe and allow us to just go
forward and you should feel
you should feel a bunch of stuff going
on but most ofly it should be going on
in the in your in your
hamstring now this one is more about
forward rotation of the spine I mean
forward you know bending of the
spine um it's also a little bit about
rotation uh and then we're going to do
the other one now normally you it would
be kind of a jump through here another
thing about a stranga is there's a
variation of this where they have their
foot here like this don't try this you
blow your knee out and I've never been
able to do it I don't I don't think it's
healthy frankly I think there's a lot of
manga poses that are really intensely
bad on your knees and I don't do them I
don't think they have scientific basis
and evidence and and uh there's some
good people that agree with me including
Ron Steiner who is my favorite asangi in
the world besides Dave Swanson he's a
German who's modified he's also a
licensed physical therapist and he's
modified a stronger for the people that
practice with him based on modern
science and it's he's just he's absolute
specimen of a human being he's
absolutely
amazing um I almost went to Germany to
practice under him he does a lot of
things like a lot of the standing a
stronga poses he does them he makes them
do them seated first so they can get the
flexibility and the ability to do it
before they do the Balan poses I do
think doing Balan poses is important
especially as you age and you want to be
a skater or
whatever the reason I'm talking so much
is because we're doing Yin Yoga
this is supposed to be peaceful I
promise not every practice is going to
be me
babbling I promise you I promise
you I have a really chatty babbly brain
so one of these times oh God doesn't
that feel good all right now let's do a
Vasa between that and the rotating the
other the other Mary chasa so let's do
our thing
again let's practice our let's like do
it for three breaths okay you ready
let's do our jump
back oh my god it feels so good the up
dog this is the counter poost friends
this is the counter Poe that's why it
feels so good
yay
okay same thing with the legs bring this
leg up so now we're going to twist it
though okay just kind of check your sit
bones out how are they doing on the M
your back straight and now we're going
to very and with one breath while we
exhale we're going to rotate as far as
we can we're going to put this arm here
now there let's just do that rotation
for let's
a lot of people will keep their arm up
like this their hand up I actually don't
like that because the aonga version has
you
eventually you'll be able to reach
around and grab your other arm on this
twist
so one of the modifications is this
right but I don't like that one
personally because I like hit to be
closer to what I'm eventually going to
do for a stronga which I used to do but
I'm not limmer enough to do it right now
thing that gets in the way here is your
gut one of the ways around that is to
turn yourself and then bring your thing
up if your gut's in the way nothing
wrong with that I do have a little bit
of a gut so let's do that let's rotate
with an
XL don't overdo it I'm bringing you now
you can bring your knee up and use it
for
leverage and then while you're doing
your five or six or 20
breaths every time you breathe out suck
in that
gut all the way down to the bottom level
of your gut suck in that gut and
rotate a little bit more don't overdo
it you'll feel your body loosen up you
can feel that rotation in your
spine feels so freaking
good okay
let's do the other
side and start a
rotation a I had a pop did you hear that
pop you might have to end up going to
the bathroom after this or
farting because it's ringing out all
your intestines organs and
stuff bringing in all that good blood
it's not that's not a hippie yoga thing
it's true squishes all your tissues and
when you UNS squish your tissues they
inflate with new blood oxygenated
blood so it's one of the best things
about this
okay oh that feels so good now see now I
just want to
meditate let's do that let's let's do 20
seconds of just sitting
here with our hands rested you don't
need to do Al or [__] like that I mean
you can just keep your hands on your you
know keep you balanced keep your your
back straight look forward if you want
to you can you can have a light like I
do or you can put a little candle there
or something give you something uh it's
called candle gazing it's a good way to
get your brain going
on and then just you can actually put
your hands here if you want you can cup
them and do Lotus I like to just have my
hands right here the whole point of
meditation is just be comfortable so you
can stay there a while
um let's do one song and I'm going to
actually turn this song up and we're
going to go to the end of the
song going to get me demonetized but
whatever I'm actually going to close my
eyes there's all schools of thought on
that actually no I'm going to look at my
light I'm G to look at my light yeah
just focus on the
light the intense Focus intense
concentration Jana and dinina meditation
and intense Focus those are another one
of the limbs of yoga just as much as ASA
is you don't have to do anything fancy
with your breathing
just think of the music and the
breathing and the light let everything
else go out of your mind including me
G to have thoughts are going to jump
into your mind your monkey mind is not
going to be able to let
go pretend you're a person inside your
mind watching those thoughts come in go
if you want to you can make your inhales
really deep fill the fill the oxygen all
up into the outer corners of your
lungs little prahara prahara breathing
another limb of yoga
I love my light how it changes colors
just got chills on my whole body
the original ASMR
that needs to be on my
merch yoga OG
ASMR for
one
for for
feel like that's a good time to
stop
so I wasn't going to do a
mantra but I want to
let's do the benediction the strong of
benediction don't worry it's not a devil
thing it just means that we're asking
for
peace um in the
world this is something that happens in
yoga particularly when you meditate and
you open your and you open your
hips you might have a bunch of emotion
come up like I just
did that's okay let it come up that's
what it's
for so uh repeat the benediction after
me um it's a call and repeat thing
[Music]
mAh mahisha
locasto
[Music]
B om sh shant
Shanty
[Music]
Shanty namaste
all right that feels
fantastic I am emotionally kind of a
mess right now but I'll try to take your
uh try to take your questions
yeah there's lots of it's lots of stuff
there that's conscious of your health
yeah you kind of need to be oh Jim and
lift weights trans yeah I used to do
that when I was a triathlete we used to
go to the you know Triathlon uh training
and going to the gym can be sort of a
form of yoga um anything that has
repetitive breathing
or you know the whole Zen In The Art of
weight training right you can make make
it doesn't have to be you versus your
body it can be you working with your
body and that's the only thing I would
suggest and it's interesting that the
creator of
P90X the inventor of the CrossFit
movement believes the same Tony
Horton it's not about you kicking your
body's ass it's about you working with
your body it's like okay body let's do
this right it's not you versus your body
it's you and your body together and mind
that's what it is that is the holistic
approach to health and it will
work
um yoga routine we talk about it I I
just do yoga every morning uh in the
past I did aanga yoga half primary um
just for the repetitiveness of it but
I've since decided to change my yoga
practice uh and have it be more of a yin
yoga I wanted to be more what we did
today the yoga that we did today served
all of the major purposes That I Want
from my yoga practice right now I get a
kickass workout every day for two and a
half hours on the bike at 4:00 in the
morning I want
to release the tension that I built in
my body during that workout and I want
it to be meditative I want it to be a
moment where I spend with me and my body
my soul and you know the energy of that
world around me which means thinking
through what I want to do during the day
it means bringing my I want to do yoga I
want to calm the fluctuations of my mind
so that when I go forth to work I'm in a
good place I'm not ripping my my wife's
head off yelling at her for some stupid
reason I'm not obsessed about the wrong
things I'm not in fear of the state of
humanity I can I can be sad about where
we are and I can try to do my best but
that's what I want out of my yoga I want
a better mental state and I want the the
recovery uh recovery from the biking so
that it complement my biking and doesn't
go against it there was a couple days
where I did full-blown a shun and I was
sweating bullets and I was you know
having a good time and then I tried to
do yoga at the same time I tried to go
out for you know three-hour bike ride at
the end of the day and being 56 that
knocked me on my ass next day I had to
sleep almost 10 hours to
cover so my take somebody asked about my
practice so my take is you know the
meditative part of yoga the the yin yoga
and you're going to see me probably
practicing more yin yoga and I'm right
now I'm going to use some of my Sunday
morning I'm going to go drink coffee and
I'm going to go study about yin yoga and
um I'm G to um look into that a little
bit more and that'll probably be more of
my practice if you wanted to know but
again I said at the beginning of the
video make yoga into what you need if
you're not doing anything active the
rest of the day maybe you want a more
active yoga maybe a Power Yoga maybe a
hot yoga maybe that makes you you know I
used to do hot yoga to remind myself it
was summer and it wasn't winter outside
you know painting your room saffron
which is what I did and putting you know
you know like a the spiral on my ceiling
out of Christmas lights and and and
heating up the room it made me remember
what summer was like in the middle of
the dead of winter when it was all
depressed so yoga is about building a
personal practice it's what you need and
that's why I keep talking about it
because I hate it when people come at
yoga the way some people come at
religion they're like tell me what to do
you know or or or physical fitness tell
me tell me what workout is going to work
for me tell me what my diet should be
you've got to do the work to learn what
you need for you and that goes for
learning Tech that goes for learning
careers that goes for anything it become
becoming one with yourself becoming at
one with yourself and understanding what
you want and what you are about not what
somebody else is going to tell you
anybody who tells you to do what they
do might want to question that because
that means that they don't accept the
truth in my and I'm doing it right
now whatever you do don't do what people
tell you to do and I just told you not
to do what people tell you to do which
is something that I told you to
do I can't win all right here we go I I
think it's more of a sharing
sharp
sharp well that's for you you do
whatever you want for
you uh yeah someone's giving me
someone's back channeling me telling me
how to do my own
yoga probably a bad idea
so winess is saying that there's a lot
of poses if they were to do that they'd
be totally messed up afterwards okay and
I they're just joining us so at the
beginning of the video I said this at
the beginning of the video I said the
reason that I'm putting this video on
YouTube the reason that I'm talking is
because rather than have me do a stronga
for for for n you know for 60 minutes to
90 minutes and seeing me do a headstand
and all this fancy stuff and pigeon and
everything and having somebody on Twitch
see me or on YouTube see me and try to
do it end up killing
themselves I felt I felt if I'm going to
do a live stream if I'm G to put it on
YouTube I might as well talk through
some of it and tell you why they didn't
I'm going to say this you're going to
get tired of hearing me say this find
your yoga find your poses find what you
need listen to your body and don't don't
harm your body aa aa it's one of the
it's one of the it means nonviolence
against
yourself uh translation I couldn't do
that most likely a scarf would slip off
my leg and hit me on the face oh
yeah it's dangerous at least for
you you should first of all okay so
somebody was saying that doing something
like this is
dangerous um oh you are you talking
about that one or this one yeah the
reason that I use this one is it's more
grippy but if you if you have so much
tension if there is so much tension on
the thing that if you let go you're
going to go flying forward you're
putting way too much tension in my
opinion you're putting way too much
tension you're just going to the outer
edge of your limit you're not pushing
your
limit okay that's not what it's about
it's about finding your limits and going
there and just making it a little bit
uncomfortable but not not to the point
where you would crash your face into the
ground if you let go that's that would
that would that's that that's no s
yeah you know that one um and in general
there are many positions in which I
could get stuck and then they would
untangle
me well that okay so again find your
yoga find your yoga and if you need help
finding poses for you then do that and
and I I'm I'm really glad that you guys
came in here and talked to me about this
because you really solidified my
decision to make sure that I'm talking
during my yoga practice because I'm
going to have to say it over and over
and over again find the poses for you if
you truly want to know you know what's
the best for you find poses do them
properly don't push your limits and and
don't do what someone else is telling
you to do there yoga is not about
touching your toes or doing a pose it's
about a better mental state and being in
being overall in health and wellness
okay so I I'm sound like a broken record
at that point um and I realize I've just
lost all my meditative Zen that had me
you know in tears doing my
chant that's the price I'm going to have
to pay for doing a live stream while I
do my yoga and
um I imagine some days I will do yoga
and I will not stream
it um but
uh but if I'm going to talk about yoga
and I'm going to be putting myself out
there on the YouTube and on live stream
if people know I do yoga I can at least
uh offer hopefully some constructive
criticism about and I mean some feedback
or whatever about helping you get to a
place where you're doing your yog I I
truly believe there there's a saying and
this is a great thing to end with okay
there's a saying in yoga um it's
actually
patan um Pabi Joyce
who's very complex character uh I I
won't go into it if you want to know all
the drama related to him you know I
already told you some of it but but one
of the saying that he has from manga is
he says yoga goes do your
yoga uh uh Yoga Yoga Yoga and all is
coming and all is coming and what he
means
is don't overthink it right and and here
I am overthinking it right don't
overthink it just do your yoga listen to
your body and then and I God I need to
hear this all the time this is why I'm
saying I'm saying it for
myself and all is coming and when he say